Guide to the Leonard Eugene Root Papers, 1923-1983
Department of Special Collections
Root, Leonard Eugene, Papers,
1923-1983
M0635
Root, Leonard Eugene, 1910-1992
11.75 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The papers include personal correspondence, memos and notes from Root's work (particularly at Lockheed), speeches, newsclippings, photographs (including some in yearbooks, 1929-1935) and publications.
Administrative Information
Access
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Sheryl Root, 1992.
Biography
Leonard Eugene Root was born in Lewiston, Idaho on July 4, 1910. He spent his school years in Stockton, California, and then attended the College of the Pacific, receiving his Bachelor of Arts in Engineering and Mathematics in 1932.
L. Eugene Root's long and distinguished career in aeronautical and space sciences began with his graduate work at California Institute of Technology in the Guggenheim Aeronautical Laboratory. He earned Masters of Sciences in both Mechanical Engineering (1933) and Aeronautical Engineering (1934) from Caltech. Before he could finish his doctoral work, however, he was recruited: by his professor, Arthur E. Raymond, also the Chief Engineer at Douglas Aircraft Company, Inc., to work at Douglas in 1934. He remained at Douglas as Chief of Aerodynamics until 1946, and then served as a member of the staff of a Special Engineering Project until 1948.
After Douglas, Rand Corporation hired him as Chief of Aircraft Division from 1948-1953. In 1953, he joined Lockheed Aircraft Corporation where he remained until his retirement in 1970. Throughout his years at Lockheed, Root was instrumental in long range planning for the corporation. He was responsible for initiating planning efforts toward corporate diversification and the development of missile and space system programs. As the first Director of the Development and Planning Department, he proposed the creation of the Missile Systems Division to develop ballistic missiles and satellites. Lockheed Missiles and Space Company, Root's brainchild, was established in January 1954.
In 1956, he was appointed Vice President of Lockheed Aircraft Corpoaration and General Manager of Missiles and Space Division. In 1959, he became Group Vice President of Lockheed Missiles and Space Division, Lockheed Electronics Company and Grand Central Rocket Company. In 1961, he was named President of Lockheed Missiles and Space Company, and in 1969, he became Group Vice President of Lockheed Aircraft Corporation. While at Lockheed, he gave priority to cultivating effective management skills as well as to developing goals for the corporation. His primary areas of research were aircraft design; flying qualities; systems and operational analyses in military sciences; development planning methods; missiles and spacecreaft and aerospace management. Among the preeminant engineering projects in which he participated were the Polaris, the Agena and the Genesis efforts.
Root was called upon as advisor to other organizations in his field. He lectured at California Institute of Technology in 1937-1938. He served as a consultant to Hughes Aircraft Aerodynamic Advisory Panel. He was a member of Aerodynamic Committee of the National Advisory Committee in Aeronautics from1944-1950. He was the Chairman of the Aerodynamic Advisory Panel for the Atomic Energy Commission between 1948 and 1950. He was first Assistant to the Deputy Chief of Staff and then Chief of Staff of the Advisory Board for Development for the United States Airforce.
Root was active in the professional, social and community organizations with which he associated. Root was active in his memberships to the National Academy of Sciences; the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics; the American Astronautical Society; and the Royal Aeronautical Society.
Dedicated to his community, Root served on the Board of Directors for the University of the Pacific, the Stanford Bank, and for the Management Council for Bay Area Employment Opportunity.
Among his honors are the Junior Chamber of Commerce Award for Outstanding Young Men (1945), the Navy Distinguished Public Service Award (1960), and a NASA Public Service Award for outstanding contributions in the Gemini Program (1966)
Root married Laura Beryl Mount in 1935. They had three children: Kirby, Karen and Brian. Root retired early from Lockheed in 1970 due to coronary disease. He turned to amateur radio to fill his free time. He died in Menlo Park, California on January 23, 1992.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
The L. Eugene Root papers document the personal side of a man dedicated a career in the aerospace industry throughout the 1940s, 5Os and 6Os. Although the collection contains some of his business notebooks, with jottings, and some interoffice communication, much of his work was in a high security environment that forbade the public dispersal of his working papers. The papers do document the success of huge projects at Lockheed through press releases, promotional literature and news clippings that Root loyally collected. In a 1980 interview, he affirmed the importance of documenting the history of the aerospace industry, and with these papers, he has contributed to its historical documentation.
Boxes 1 through 4 contain Root's biographical papers. Included are limited tax and medical papers, a transcribed interview, an autobiography, early family correspondence (particularly with his wife in 1945 - 1946), acquaintence correspondence, and memorabilia that he collected, some of which pertains to his association with the University of the Pacific and the California Institute of Technology.
The remaining boxes, 5 through 21, contain the material he collected relating to his aerospace career and to the space industry in general. Boxes 5 through 7 house memorabilia and keep sakes that Rootcollected. Included also are articles by Root as well as literature about various aerospace organizations. Extensive newsclippings are stored in Box 8, and in Box 9, is Lockheed business material mostly pertaining to Root's responsibilities as manager at Lockheed. Box 10 holds issues of The Lockheed Star (May 14, 1953-October 18, 1985), a publication of the Lockheed Missiles and Space Company, Inc. In box 11 are miscellaneous reports, notes, and news releases. Boxes 12,13 and 14 contain space industry related publications. In Boxes 15 through 18 are professional photographs of Root as well as photographs of various Lockheed events.
With his papers, Stanford received a number of books from Root's personal library. Because of their interest to the libraries' patrons they have been removed to the public stacks. A list of those volumes is available upon request. A small number of volumes, including pamphlets and books not suitable for cataloguing, remain with the papers because of their significance in Root's life. These volumes are sometimes filed with other appropriate material and the rest are stored in Boxes 19, 20 and 21.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Douglas Aircraft Company.; Lockheed Aircraft Corporation.; Rand Corporation.; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration.; Aeronautics, Military.; Aerospace industries.; Rocketry.; Science--History.; The Naranjado: College of the Pacific yearbook.
Collection Contents
- Series 1: Personal Papers
  - Medical papers: L.E. Root (c.l957) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tax records (1939-1944) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Selected Obituaries (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Maynard Pennell (Retirement Announcement, 1974) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings - unrelated to career (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Honors (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clubs (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Sketches & Award Nominations (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Autobiography (1970) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Biographical info - Career (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings - Biographical (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Interview with L.E. Root (1980) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Memorabilia - Root's Children (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Family & Personal Letters (1945 - 46) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Family Letters (1968-1969) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Family Papers (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cards, Notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Calendar, Notes (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cards (Birthday, Get We1l, Fathers' Day)(1961-62) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence (1945 - 48) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence (1953 - 54) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Personal Correspondence (1955 - 58) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence (1959 - 61) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence (1966) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence (1967) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Personal Notes, Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence (1968 - 69) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence - "Special Friends" (1954, 1958, 1962 - 69) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence (1973) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence (1979) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Retirement - Amateur Radio (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Some Considerations in Case of Death" (Retirement papers, 1971) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Articles on "The University" (1963 - 67) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Stockton High School (1928) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - University of The Pacific (Bulletin, 1964; Commencement, 1932) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pacific Review (Oct. 1978) (3 copies) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - California Institute of Technology re: Professorship (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The California Institute Forum (1947 - 48) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Trips (Brochures, memorabilia) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Sermons by Ray C. Stednian (Peninsula Bible Church, 1965) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Speaking Engagements (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Map of Mindego Hill, CA Quadrangle (1961) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series 2: Professional Papers
  - "Keepsakes / Scrapbook - Clippings, Pamphlets, Letters, LMSC, LEC" (1959 - 62) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Keepsakes / Scrapbook - Clippings, Pamphlets, Letters, LMSC, LEC" (1959 - 63) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "Keepsakes / Scrapbook - Clippings, Pamphlets, Letters, LMSC, LEC" (1959 - 62) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Scrapbook" (1958-1965) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Scrapbook" (1966-1969) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Scrapbook" (1970) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Diagrams - Airplanes (1940's) (Glen L. Martin Co.) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Douglas Aircraft Company, Inc. (1943 - 48) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Rand Corporation (1952 - 53) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Scientists at War; The Birth of the Rand Corporation" (c. 1983) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - American Rocket Society, American Astronautical Society, American Institute~of Aeronautic and Astronautics (1962) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Aerospace Science (1958 - 1962) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - National Academy of Engineering - Material on Biography of William Mentzer (1972) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Trajectory (Winter 1960 - 61) - "Special Polaris Report" (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Polaris Submarine (Notes and Articles, 1958 - 65) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Articles by L.E. Root (Box 7, Folder 10)
    "Dynamic Longitudinal Stability Charts for Design Use," 1935; "Empennage Design with Single and Multiple Vertical Surfaces," 1939; "The Effective Use of Aerodynamic Balances," 1945; "The Role of the Missile Industry in Astronautics," 1958; "Some Observations in the Challenging Aspects of the Telementry Field," 1959
  - Additional Articles by L.E. Root (1956, 1959) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    On the organization of the corporation:"Development Planning For Management Decision," 1956; "Long Range Planning at Lockheed, " 1956; "Linear Organization Charts," 1959
  - Papers by Ira C. Eaker (1966 - 67) re: Vietnam War (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - William F. Whitmore - Correspondence (1975 - 79) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Professional Notes (1967 - 69) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "Trident Project History" (1983) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases F1O4 Starfighter (c.l958) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "The War of Wits" - Fortune Magazine (1951) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Space Industry: Newsclippings (1934 - 48) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Space Industry: Newsclippings (1953 - 56) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Space Industry: Newsclippings (1956 - 59) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Space Industry: Newsclippings (1959 - 61) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Space Industry: Newsclippings (1961 - 69) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Space Industry: Newsclippings (1969 - 76) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Articles - Science & Technology (1963) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Various Addresses (1959 - 60, 1966) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Lockheed - Miscellaneous Papers (c. 1970) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Newsclippings (1969 - 83) (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Series 3: LOCKHEED ADMINISTRATIVE NOTES, REPORTS, AND CORRESPONDENCE
  - Lockheed Burbank (1953) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Lockheed (1952 - 56) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Lockheed (1957 - 59) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Lockheed (1959 - 61) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lockheed (1961 - 66), 5 Printed Materials and Photographs & 6 Notes (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Spacecraft Entry and Landing in Planetary Atmospheres" - Lockheed Publication (1962) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lockheed: Notes (1961-1966) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lockheed: Interoffice Correspondence (1961-1966) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lockheed (1967) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Lockheed (1968) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Lockheed (1969) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Lockheed (1969) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Lockheed (1975 - 77, 1979, 1980) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Lockheed Star (1953-1985, including 25th Anniversary issue, May, 1979) (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Series 4: MISCELLANEOUS REPORTS, NOTES, NEWS RELEASES
  - Country Almanac (1981) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Lockheed - Jetstar (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - L.E. Root - Personal and Business Notes (1949 - 59) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - L.E. Root - Personal and Business Notes (1948 - 60) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Name cards of acquaintences (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Series 5: VARI0US PUBLICATIONS: SPACE INDUSTRY RELATED
  - Aerojet General Corporation (1959) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Aerospace Industries Association of America: "Space Exploration: A Higher Vision," by H.H. Humphrey (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - American Astronautical Society Newsletter, 1973. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - American Ordinance Association: "Conquest of Outer Space," by Dr. Wernher von Braun. 1960. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - American Quarterly Review: "The Delicate Balance of Terror," 1959; and "Two Ways of Life," 1962. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - American Society for Industrial Security: "Industrial Security," 1959. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Apogee, August, 1965. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Arnold Engineering Development Letter: "Aro Inc. Rocket Test Facility 1964." (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Asne Day 1968. (Reprinted.from Naval Engineers Journal, June, 1965). (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science: "Science and the Space Program." 1966. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Bell Aerosystems Company: Rendezvous (Vol III, No 4, 1964). September-October, 1963. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - California Institute of Technology: "Science for Mankind" by Ronald Reagan (1967). (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Cruiser Destroyer Force, US Atlantic Fleet: "Welcome Aboard." (n.d.). (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Current. March, 1962. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Douglas Corporation: "Douglas Airview." (October 1945, February 1946) (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - EI Depont DeNemours and Company - 2 Speeches. (1963, 1965) (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Fortune. (October, 1977) (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Head Quarters USAF - "Guide to Staff Administration." (1951) (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Institute for Aeronautical Sciences: "Results of Experiments in Space." (1961) (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - The International Academy of Astronautics: "The First Decade." (1970) (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - "Introduction to Outer Space" and "The Navy's Terrible Weapon" (Reader's Digest, 1959) (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory. "DASCO Countdown Events." (April 1964) (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Lockheed: "Lockheed Pathways to the Stars" (1957) (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Lockheed: "Man on the Moon" (c. 1961) (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Lockheed: "Agena" (1956-1966) (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Lockheed: "Gemini Press Site" (c. 1966) (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Lockheed: "Gemini Agena Target Press Handbook" (c. 1966) (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Lockheed: "Systems Management Experience" (1967) (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Lockheed: Speeches by Lockheed Executives. (including L.E. Root) (1961-1965) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lockheed: Organizational Manual. (c.197l) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lockheed: Lockheed Horizons. (History of Lockheed) (1983) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lockheed: Lockheed-Georgia Company (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Lockheed: "Way Outer Space" by Dick Shaw (n.d.) Cartoons. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "M65l Gama Goat Standard 'A'" (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Maps and Charts (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "Missile, Space and Range Pioneers" (Yearbook, 1967) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - NASA: "Voyager I Encounter with Jupiter" (March 1979) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - NASA: Mercury Atlas - 9 (1963) (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - NASA: "Speaking of Space and Aeronautics" Lecture Series (1966-68) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - NASA: "St. Louis Bicentennial Space Symposiums" (1964-1965) With L.E. Root's Notes. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - NASA: Voyager (1980) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - NASA: Manned Space Flight 1966. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - National Academy of Engineering: 1977: "Innovators and Entrepeneurs-An Endangered Species?" 1979: "Engineers and Public Affairs" by David Packard. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - National Academy of Sciences: News Report (May 1973) (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - National Planning Association - "Looking Ahead" Vol 13, No 6. Articles by Root: The Return on our Investments in Space Exploration." (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Naval Armament Journal (August 1964) (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Navy (March 1962) (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Rand: Annual Report 1969. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Space Age News (April 13, 1959). (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Stanford Review (Nov. - Dec., 1963) (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Time (January 14, 1946; August 1, 1960) (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Understanding, (March 1960) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - United States Airforce: "Ten Years of Air Force Ballistic Missle and Space Progress (May 1954-May 1964) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Wilbur and Orville Wright, 'The Birth of Aerospace (1900-1909)'" (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Wilbur Wright Memorial Lecture: "Aviation in Perspective" (1965) by Edward Heinemann (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "The Wings Club" (Yearbook 1950-1951) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Diagnosis Guides and Medical Charts" (1958) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "The Warm Water Game Fishes of California"; "Pocket Guide to Animal Tracks" (1958); "American Woodland Trees" (1964) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "Hobby Publications" (1955); "Pocket Billiards" (1959) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Hunting and Waterfowl Instruction Booklets (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - National Rifle Association Publications (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Fireman's Insurance; Beta Gamma Sigma Society (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - The Von Karman Institute for Fluid Dynamics: Announcement of Preparation of Collected Works (1963) (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Series 6: PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Photographs (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Photographs Printed for Space, the New Frontier (1953) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Old Photo of L.E. Root & Airplane (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Photographs (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Visit to Lockheed Photos (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - L.E. Root - Head & Shoulder Portraits (1961 - 69) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - L.E. Root Photo (1934 - 48) & Cartoons (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Photos of Root and Military (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Young Root (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Photos of Root & Others (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Space Photos (NASA) (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Golf Team (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Retired Root (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Expanded Employment Opportunities Program Banquet Photos (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Photos of Root, Airplane, X-mas Record (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Photographs: Polaris (1968) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Lockheed Touraine Vehicle (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 1965 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 1966 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - L.E. Root with Employer (1965) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Mrs. L.E. Root (1966) "Cape Photos" (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lockheed Aircraft Corporation (April 1966) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Herschel Brown's Retirement (February 1967) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Root's Visit to Cape Kennedy, Jetstar Flight (1968) (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Photographs (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Photographs (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: NASA Photos (1964) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Lockheed Photos (1967) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - L.E. Root & General Schriever (1959) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Photos (c. 1965) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - American Astronautical Society (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Lockheed Recreation Association Picnic (1965), Man of Year Award (1969) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - LERA Golf Tournament (1965 - 68) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Photos (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Root W/ Navy Officers (1964) (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Root with Employees (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Transquest (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Navy League Show / Enterprise II (1965) (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Photos, Gemini Pictures (1959, 1966 - 67) (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Misc. Photos (c.l962) (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Series 7: PHOTOGRAPHS, NOTEBOOKS, AND MEMORABILIA
  - Project "Gulliver" Notebook (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - NASA - Space Shuttle (1976) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Oversize Matted Photos: Root w/ Military, Gross, Proofsheet (1968), I.J. Galatin TJSN (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Distinguished Service Award (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Information Sheets - Lockeed Missiles & Space Vehicles / Satellites (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Ocean Floor Depth Map, Souvenir Menu (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Series 8: OVERSIZED PHOTOGRAPHS, NOTEBOOKS, AND MEMORABILIA
  - Mounted Missiles & Space Weekly Cover (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Lockheed Cartoon Book / Chronical of Aviation (1949) (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Adventures in Partnership - Story of Polaris (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Holiday in San Francisco Magazine (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Lockheed Star (1959, 1967) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Oversize Pictures - Lockheed, Land Vehicle, Project Gemini (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Photos = Root with H. H. Humphrey, Root Family (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - X-Large Photos - Root w/ Raborn & Unidentified, Lockheed, Gemini Project (autographed by crew) (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Series 9: BOOKS
  - Adams, St. Clair, and Joseph Morris, eds. It Can Be Done; Poems of Inspirations. New York: George Sully & Company, 1921. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Aerospace Corporation, Trevor Gardener, 1915-1963. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - American Geneologies, The Root Family Album. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Lincoln Laboratory. 1963. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Rand Corporation. The First Fifteen Years. Santa Monica, 1963. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Stieglitz, Harold. Organization Planning. New York: national Industrial Conference Board, Inc., 1962. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Thomas, Shirley. Men of Space, Volume 5. New York: Chilton Books, 1962. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - United States Air Force Scientific Advisory Board, Its First Twenty Years. 1944-1964. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Weaver, Warren. A Great Age for Science. New York: Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1960. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Boland, Lawrence F. Beryllium: Present and Potential Uses. Reading, PA: The Beryllium Corp., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Cosmos Club. Membership of the Cosmos Club. Washington D.C.: Cosmos Club, 1968. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Department of the Navy. US Naval Weapons Laboratory. 1965. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Dugdale, H.K. How to Cet Along WIth People and Get Ahead In Your Job. Maryland: The Kirkley Press, 1954. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Engstrom, Elmer W. Charles Proteus Steinmetz Centennial Memorial Lecture. 1965. (Box 21, Folder 5)